## **Benjamin Hoath**

### **Hybrid Digital / Web Designer**

A creative and accomplished designer with well over a decade of combined freelance and agency experience, including an extensive range of skills, technical knowledge, and a hunger to design beautiful and meaningful experiences.

Now eager to push into a more dedicated role in website / user interface / product design that requires a talented and experienced senior designer keen to mix their love of design with web development.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **DIGITAL DESIGNER, PLAYNE DESIGN**MAY 2021 – PRESENT

- Consistently delivering high-end design work and maintaining relationships with our clients, including East Sussex County Council, De La Warr Pavilion, Lambeth Council, Creative Estuary, Balfour Winery, London SC1, Visit 1066, GoodData
- Wearing many hats including lead designer, design support to the creative director, administration assistant, problem-solver, illustrator, proof-reader, typesetter, tutor, learner, IT guru, studio dog minder and walker
- Achieving real results with the work that we produce, measured in ways such as:
  - The positive impacts on tourism in Sussex (Sussex Modern)
  - Exposure at government-run events at Parliament (Sussex Wine Tourism)
  - Sign-up of new users to a product (GoodData)
  - Client satisfaction with work delivered and relationships sustained (Creative Estuary)

## **DOCUMENT BRANDING SPECIALIST, AXA HEALTH**DEC 2020 – JUN 2021

- Utilised Adobe InDesign to successfully implement AXA Health's new branding across a suite of customer and personnel-facing documents
- Recognised as both mentor and ambassador of the document creation team. Dedicated a portion of my day to designing and developing a video course / tutorial programme to support team members with using InDesign for future document creation and branding
- Significantly improved the usability of the branding style structure using InDesign to increase productivity by 300%.

#### **FURTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Freelance Brand Designer, Sublime Design Aug 2019 – May 2021

Content Manager, Sussex Downs Fertility Centre Mar 2020 – Jul 2020 Senior Designer & Prepress Manager, Judges Mar 2017 – 2020

Delivery Personnel, UPS Nov – Jan 2017 Sabbatical for travelling Aug – Oct 2016

Printer / Designer, A&S Services Ltd Jul 2013 – Jul 2016



#### **CONTACT DETAILS**

+44 07425604633 benhoath@icloud.com linkedin.com/in/benhoath

#### **TOOLS**

- Adobe Creative Suite CC
- Figma
- · Visual Studio Code
- Miro
- Notion
- ClickUp
- · Google Suite

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Web / Product / UX UI design
- · Print design and processes
- Photo artworking / editing
- Illustration
- HTML5 / CSS3 / JS
- · Mac & Windows proficient

# EDUCATION & DEVELOPMENT

2023 - ongoing:

freeCodeCamp

2017:

SOAS University of London JLPT N5

2008 - 2011:

University of Portsmouth BA Hons Illustration

#### **PORTFOLIO**



www.benhoath.com



instagram.com/designthatssublime



instagram.com/levelmyb3d